Guide to the PWA Health Group records, 1990-1991
PWA Health Group records, 1990-1991
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
PWA Health Group. Records, 1990-1991
7528
PWA Health Group
2.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, notes, bibliographies, articles, conference programs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, notes, bibliographies, articles, and conference programs related to AIDS, particularly new drugs for the treatment of opportunistic infections and the specific issues relating to women with AIDS. Includes correspondence with drug companies and files about the Countdown/18 Months Plan of ACT UP/NY's Treatment and Data Committee.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
PWA (People With AIDS) Health Group formed in New York City in 1987 to facilitate access to experimental drugs for the treatment of HIV/AIDS-related infections. The Countdown/18 Months Plan was a plan to make the five major opportunistic infections which claim the most lives treatable in the next year and one-half.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, notes, bibliographies, articles, and conference programs related to AIDS, particularly new drugs for the treatment of opportunistic infections and the specific issues relating to women with AIDS. Includes correspondence with drug companies and files about the Countdown/18 Months Plan of ACT UP/NY's Treatment and Data Committee.
SUBJECTS
Names:
PWA Health Group.
Subjects:
AIDS (Disease).; HIV infections.; Medical care--New York (N.Y.).; Drug utilization.; Pharmaceutical policy.; Opportunistic infections.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Box 1
Series II. Conferences
Box 1
Series III. Organizations
Box 1
Series IV. Subject Files
AIDS
Box 1
General
Boxes 1-2
Notebooks
Box 2
Miscellaneous Supporting Materials
Box 2
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Incoming Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Incoming Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Incoming Correspondence, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Outgoing Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Form letters, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II. Conferences
  - AIDSCOM: 6th International Conference on AIDS, San Francisco, CA, June 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - AIDS Activist Conference--People of Color, 1990 [?] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AIDS Clinical Trial Group Meeting, Bethesda, MD, March 5-7, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - AIDS-Related Opportunistic Infections: Developing Effective Therapies, April 9-10, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ATAC (AIDS Treatment Activists Coalition), Washington, D.C., November 10-11, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Anglogenesis Blocking Research (notes re: conference), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Clinical Manifestations and Therapeutics, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Clinical Trial Design: Efficacy Evaluation of Anti-HIV Agents, Chicago, IL, April 29-30, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Women and HIV Infection, Washington, D.C., December 13-14, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series III. Organizations
  - ACT-UP/Chicago, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - ACT-UP/Los Angeles, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ACT-UP/New York, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ACT-UP/Seattle, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - ACTG Committee (AIDS Clinical Trial Group), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Atra Corporation, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - CDC (Center for Disease Control), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - CBCTN (Community Based Clinical Trials Network), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - CIBA-GEIGY Corporation, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Columbia Gay Health Advocacy Project, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - COMBAT, Southwest (Community Based AIDS Treatment Group), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Division of Antiviral Drug Products, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Dynamic Information, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - F-D-C Reports, Inc., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Liposome Corporation, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - National Committee to Review Current Procedures for Approval of New Drugs for Cancer and AIDS, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - National Library of Medicine, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - OI Committee (Opportunistic Infections), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - People of Color Caucus of the Community Constituency Group, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Association, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Planning Council (New York City), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Statistical Working Group/Methodology, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Treatment and Data Committee: Countdown Eighteen Months Working Group, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Treatment Education, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 41a)
  - Women's AIDS Network, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 42a)
- Series IV. Subject Files
  - AIDS
    - 2-CDA (Box 1, Folder 41b)
    - Alpha-Interferon Therapy (Box 1, Folder 42b)
    - B19 Parvovirus (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - B-Carotine+E (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - CMV (Cytomegalovirus) (Box 1, Folder 45-46)
    - CNS Lymphoma (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - DHPG (Ganciclovir) (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Doxorubicin Solution (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Kaposi Sarcoma (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Lymphoma (Box 1, Folder 51-52)
    - Neoplasms (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Pentosan Polysulfate (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Peptide T (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Reiter's Disease (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Rifabutin (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - WIN57273 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - General
    - Bibliographies, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Bristol Myers, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Cancer, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Catalogs, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Children, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Education, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Education: Health Care Workers, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - FDA (Food and Drug Administration), 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - FDA Action (Food and Drug Administration), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - HIV, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Latinos/Latinas, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Information, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Nervous System, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Nutrition, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Phase One Now! 1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Policy: costs, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Policy: testing and screening, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Posters/flyers, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Press releases, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Prevention, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Prisoners: Albany Action, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Product List, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Project Inform, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Publications, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
    - Transcripts, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Transmission, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
    - Transmission: Perinatal, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Women, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 21-24)
    - Women: ACTG Protocol 076 (AIDS Clinical Trial Group), 1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Notebooks
    - Notebooks: "General Chemistry," "Fall/Winter:" includes notes from Countdown 18 Months meetings, phone numbers, drafted letters, etc., 1990 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
  - Miscellaneous Supporting Materials
    - Unlabelled notes, messages, phone lists, etc., 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Periodicals Separated from #7528:
AIDS Surveillance Update: Dec. 1990; Jan. 1991
AIDS Treatment News: no. 108 (1990); nos. 122, 125, 129, 132-133, 138, 140-141 (1991)
AIDS Update: May 4, Aug. 24, Aug. 10, Sept. 21, Nov. 2 1990
Being Alive/Long Beach Newsletter: June, Sept. 1991
BOTA (Bulletin of Experimental Treatment for AIDS): Nov. 1988; June 1989; Aug., Nov. 1990
Bulletin: State Communities AID Association: Dec. 1990
CFIDS Chronicle: Mar. 1991
Dallas Buyer's Club Newsletter: May 1991
Dateline: National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases: Sept. 1991
Digest: A Review of Issues addressed by ACT UP's T + D committee during its past week of activities: nos. 87-88, 96, 99-103, 105-106, 118-199 (1991)
Health Care for All: Mar. 14 1991
HIV/AIDS Surveillance: Mar., July, Aug. 1991
New York Citizens' AIDS Lobby Alert: Apr. 23 1991
News from ICAAC (Interscience Conference on Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy): 1990
NewSource: Oct. 1991
Notes from the Underground: Jan., July/Aug. 1991
PWA Coalition Newsline: July/Aug. 1991
STNews: Jan. 1991
The Blue Sheet: Feb. 6 1991
Treatment Issues: Nov. 30 1990; Mar. 28, May 15, Aug. 30. 1991
Treatment Issues Bulletins: Oct. 1991
Treatment Issues Report: v.2, no.8; v.2, no.11 1992
Treatment Update: May 1991
U.S. Regulatory Reporter: Apr. 1989
UMTFA (Upper Manhattan Task Force on AIDS): Fall 1991